Leeds, UK
Portfolio
Linkedin
Github

Andre Vassell

07554006954 andrevassell89@gmail.com

Junior Front-End Developer

Currently a Firefighter making my career change into the world of technology. I first experienced coding by accident when I was at university through my degree in Media Technology. Since then, my curiosity for technology expanded when I realised how it can positively change lives by providing people with access to information and resources that they would not otherwise have, this makes me very captivated by digital products. I have a desire for Software Engineering, a passion for creating pioneering applications and fascination for all things tech.

A flexible and adaptable person that ensures maximum productivity, strategic and creative thinking. Excellent time management skills with an eye for detail. A very resilient individual gained from experience from the Fire and Rescue Service, this can be adapted to everyday life and projects.

Technologies, Languages and Professional Skills

- React
- React Native
- Next.is
- Tailwindcss
- Node IS
- Jest
- TDD
- GitHub
- Firebase

- TypeScript
- Javascript
- Swift
- HTML

- Growth mindset
- Accountable
- Collaborative

Projects

- <u>'Travel App'</u> Made in React Native, using REST APIs, Stack Navigation, React Native Async Storage, React
 UseState Hooks, React Native Testing.
- 'My Portfolio' Made using Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwindcss deployed with vercel.

Certifications and Courses

- Programming with JavaScript Coursera
- React Basics Coursera
- Advance React Coursera
- React Native Coursera
- Version Control Coursera
- Introduction to iOS Mobile Application Development Coursera

Experience

Junior Software Developer

March 2020 - Present

Leeds, UK

- Developer working across a range of different projects including apps and websites.
- Participated in Meta Front-End Developer course via Coursera, including programming with JavaScript React Basic,
 Advance React, React Native, GitHub/Version Control

Firefighter, West Yorkshire Fire and Rescue Service

2018 - Present

- Working as team at major incidents various types of fires, rescues, and road traffic incidents
- Works in multiple high-pressure environments within short time frames, using high level decision making
- Attend multi-agency rescue jobs involving critical thinking and teamwork
- Part of recruitment team for awareness days focusing on helping people find fulfilment and belonging in their careers
- Personal trainer lead for my team which includes influence and encouragement of leading a healthy lifestyle,
 with exercise and nutrition
- Fire Fighter Charity representative for the station, which involves organising fund raising events

Sales Assistant – Curry's 2014 - 2017

Leeds, UK

- Samsung representative for the store, which included attended launch conferences to upskill on new technology ready to promote within store
- Achieved KPI's and bonus targets every month

Education

•	BSc Media Technology, Manchester Metropolitan	2011-2014
	 HTML, CSS, Java, Python for Scripting in Autodesk Maya 	
•	BTEC Computer Networking, Leeds City College	2009-2011

Hobbies

- Olympic Weightlifting
- Outdoor adventures
- Travelling
- Cooking